<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

    <!-- Misc -->

    <Bast_CritterNotTameable>Critters live for the kill. It's all they know. You'll die before you tame one.</Bast_CritterNotTameable>
    <Bast_BahlrinNotTameable>Bahlrins exist soley to rip you limb from limb. Taming them is impossible. You're more likely to be shot in the same eye 3 times in one gunfight.</Bast_BahlrinNotTameable>

    <!-- Animal Products -->

    <Bast_Alluvium_Jelly>Alluvium Jelly Production</Bast_Alluvium_Jelly>
    <Chemfuel>Chemfuel Production</Chemfuel>
    
    <!-- Animal Stats -->
	
	<Bast_PrimaryRole>Primary Role</Bast_PrimaryRole>
	<Bast_SecondaryRole>Secondary Role</Bast_SecondaryRole>
    <Bast_TertiaryRole>Tertiary Role</Bast_TertiaryRole>
    <Bast_Movement>Movement</Bast_Movement>
	<Bast_RangedAttacks>Uses Ranged Attacks</Bast_RangedAttacks>
	<Bast_Yes>Yes</Bast_Yes>
	<Bast_No>No</Bast_No>
	<Bast_NoRanged>This animal doesn't have ranged attacks. To order for it to attack, it needs to be trained in Guard and Attack, then it needs to be assigned to follow a master when drafted and/or working. The "release" button on the master's commands bar will make the animal attack in melee.</Bast_NoRanged>
	<Bast_Ranged>This animal uses ranged attacks, and will only use melee attacks if the enemy gets into melee range. To order it to attack, it needs to be trained in Guard and Attack, then it needs to be assigned to follow a master when drafted and/or working. The "release" button on the master's commands bar will make the animal search for appropiate cover and use its ranged attack.</Bast_Ranged>

    <!-- Roles -->

    <Bast_Floater>Floater</Bast_Floater>
    <Bast_Warper>Warper</Bast_Warper>
    <Bast_Boomer>Boomer</Bast_Boomer>
    <Bast_ESDBoomer>ESD Boomer</Bast_ESDBoomer>
    <Bast_ExtinguisherBoomer>Extinguisher Boomer</Bast_ExtinguisherBoomer>
    <Bast_SmokeyBoomer>Smokey Boomer</Bast_SmokeyBoomer>
    <Bast_Farm>Farm Animal</Bast_Farm>
    <Bast_EggLayer>Egg Layer</Bast_EggLayer>
    <Bast_WeirdEater>Weird Eater</Bast_WeirdEater>
	<Bast_DamageRangedSharp>Sharp Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedSharp>
	<Bast_DamageRangedAcid>Acid Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedAcid>
    <Bast_DamageRangedFlame>Flame Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedFlame>
    <Bast_DamageRangedPlasma>Plasma Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedPlasma>
    <Bast_DamageRangedElectric>Electric Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedElectric>
    <Bast_DamageRangedSlime>Slime Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedSlime>
    <Bast_DamageRangedWind>Wind Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedWind>
    <Bast_WebShooter>Web Shooter</Bast_WebShooter>
    <Bast_ExtremeAggressor>Extreme Aggressor</Bast_ExtremeAggressor>
    <Bast_Protector>Protector</Bast_Protector>
    <Bast_Excavtor>Excavtor</Bast_Excavtor>
    <Bast_SelfRegeneration>Regeneration</Bast_SelfRegeneration>
    <Bast_PassiveRegeneration>Passive Regeneration</Bast_PassiveRegeneration>
    <Bast_NatureEffecter>Nature Effecter</Bast_NatureEffecter>
    <Bast_Effecter>Effecter</Bast_Effecter>
    <Bast_Immune>Perfectly Immune</Bast_Immune>
    <Bast_AcidImmunity>Acid Immunity</Bast_AcidImmunity>
    <Bast_NoPain>Painless</Bast_NoPain>
    <Bast_Cute>Cute</Bast_Cute>
    <Bast_Glower>Glower</Bast_Glower>

    <!-- Role Descriptions -->
	
	<Bast_FloaterDesc>This animal floats above the ground, ignoring all movement penalties.</Bast_FloaterDesc>
    <Bast_WarperDesc>This animal will sporadically teleport short distances.</Bast_WarperDesc>
    <Bast_BoomerDesc>This animal explodes on death.</Bast_BoomerDesc>
    <Bast_ESDBoomerDesc>When damaged via ranged attacks this animal has a chance to explode, subsequently releasing a strong electrostatic discharge.</Bast_ESDBoomerDesc>
    <Bast_ExtinguisherBoomerDesc>When damaged via ranged attacks this animal has a chance to explode, subsequently releasing a violent burst of air and extinguishing all nearby flames.</Bast_ExtinguisherBoomerDesc>
    <Bast_SmokeyBoomerDesc>When damaged via ranged attacks this animal has a chance to explode, subsequently releasing a giant plume of smoke and rendering visibility almost useless.</Bast_SmokeyBoomerDesc>
    <Bast_1.2FarmDesc>This is a farm animal and will produce resources over time.</Bast_1.2FarmDesc>
    <Bast_1.3FarmDesc>This is a farm animal and will produce resources over time. Needs to be penned in or it will wander off.</Bast_1.3FarmDesc>
    <Bast_EggLayerDesc>This animal will periodically lay eggs.</Bast_EggLayerDesc>
    <Bast_WeirdEaterDesc>This animal eats a very strange variety of foods.</Bast_WeirdEaterDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedSharpDesc>This animal will use ranged attacks which inflict cutting damage.</Bast_DamageRangedSharpDesc>
	<Bast_DamageRangedAcidDesc>This animal will use highly corrosive ranged attacks to inflict lasting acidic damage.</Bast_DamageRangedAcidDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedFlameDesc>This animal will spew blazing flames towards its target, most likely lighting anything in between on fire.</Bast_DamageRangedFlameDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedPlasmaDesc>This animal will shell out devastating plasma-based ranged attacks which carry the heat of an entire sun.</Bast_DamageRangedPlasmaDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedElectricDesc>This animal will unleash a hail of electrical based attacks capable of stopping a healthy heart in its tracks.</Bast_DamageRangedElectricDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedSlimeDesc>This animal will throw, spit, shoot, or launch a weird sticky substance at hostile pawns.</Bast_DamageRangedSlimeDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedWindDesc>This animal is capable of discharging tremendous gusts of blisteringly cold wind. Frost bite is a real concern.</Bast_DamageRangedWindDesc>
    <Bast_WebShooterDesc>This animal will shoot sticky, stringy, webs at foes as an attempt to slow their movement.</Bast_WebShooterDesc>
    <Bast_ExtremeAggressorDesc>This animal, regardless of mental state or physical well-being, will be extremely aggressive towards all living things.</Bast_ExtremeAggressorDesc>
    <Bast_ProtectorDesc>When properly trained, this animal will fight to protect the colony until it's dying breath.</Bast_ProtectorDesc>
    <Bast_ExcavtorDesc>This animal will periodically dig in the ground for various stones.</Bast_ExcavtorDesc>
    <Bast_SelfRegenerationDesc>Due to an unknown genetic anomaly, this animal will regenerate wounds over time.</Bast_SelfRegenerationDesc>
    <Bast_PassiveRegenerationDesc>Through this animals good graces, nearby pawns are healed of their painful physical afflictions.</Bast_PassiveRegenerationDesc>
    <Bast_NatureEffecterDesc>This animal will periodically alter vegetation, thus creating new life and unlocking potentially useful resources.</Bast_NatureEffecterDesc>
    <Bast_EffecterDesc>This animal effects the mental state of nearby pawns, for better or for worse.</Bast_EffecterDesc>
    <Bast_DiseaseImmunityDesc>This animal is immune to all known diseases.</Bast_DiseaseImmunityDesc>
    <Bast_AcidImmunityDesc>This animal is immune to all forms of acid.</Bast_AcidImmunityDesc>
    <Bast_NoPainDesc>This animal doesn't even know what pain means. It will push on, no matter how grave its injuries are.</Bast_NoPainDesc>
    <Bast_CuteDesc>Congrats. You've found an easter egg. :)</Bast_CuteDesc>
    <Bast_GlowerDesc>This animal glows like a small sun... well... maybe more like street lamp.</Bast_GlowerDesc>

</LanguageData>