<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

    <!-- Misc -->

    <Bast_CritterNotTameable>Critters live for the kill. It's all they know. You'll die before you tame one.</Bast_CritterNotTameable>
    <Bast_BahlrinNotTameable>Bahlrins exist soley to rip you limb from limb. Taming them is impossible. You're more likely to be shot in the same eye 3 times in one gunfight.</Bast_BahlrinNotTameable>

    <!-- Animal Products -->

    <Bast_Alluvium_Jelly>Alluvium Jelly Production</Bast_Alluvium_Jelly>
    <Chemfuel>Chemfuel Production</Chemfuel>
    
    <!-- Animal Stats -->
	
	<Bast_PrimaryRole>Primary Role</Bast_PrimaryRole>
	<Bast_SecondaryRole>Secondary Role</Bast_SecondaryRole>
	<Bast_RangedAttacks>Uses Ranged Attacks</Bast_RangedAttacks>
	<Bast_Yes>Yes</Bast_Yes>
	<Bast_No>No</Bast_No>
	<Bast_NoRanged>This animal doesn't have ranged attacks. To order for it to attack, it needs to be trained in Guard and Attack, then it needs to be assigned to follow a master when drafted and/or working. The "release" button on the master's commands bar will make the animal attack in melee.</Bast_NoRanged>
	<Bast_Ranged>This animal uses ranged attacks, and will only use melee attacks if the enemy gets into melee range. To order it to attack, it needs to be trained in Guard and Attack, then it needs to be assigned to follow a master when drafted and/or working. The "release" button on the master's commands bar will make the animal search for appropiate cover and use its ranged attack.</Bast_Ranged>

    <!-- Roles -->

    <Bast_Floater>Floater</Bast_Floater>
    <Bast_Boomer>Boomer</Bast_Boomer>
    <Bast_Farm>Farm Animal</Bast_Farm>
    <Bast_EggLayer>Egg Layer</Bast_EggLayer>
    <Bast_WeirdEater>Weird Eater<Bast_WeirdEater>
	<Bast_LivingFireExtinguisher>Living Fire Extinguisher</Bast_LivingFireExtinguisher>
	<Bast_LivingEMPBlast>Living EMP Blast</Bast_LivingEMPBlast>
    <Bast_LivingSmokeScreen>Living Smoke Screen</Bast_LivingSmokeScreen>
	<Bast_DamageRangedSharp>Sharp Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedSharp>
	<Bast_DamageRangedAcid>Acid Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedAcid>
    <Bast_DamageRangedFlame>Flame Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedFlame>
    <Bast_DamageRangedPlasma>Plasma Ranged Attacker</Bast_DamageRangedPlasma>

    <!-- Role Descriptions -->
	
	<Bast_FloaterDesc>This animal floats above the ground, ignoring all movement penalties.</Bast_FloaterDesc>
    <Bast_BoomerDesc>This animal explodes on death.</Bast_BoomerDesc>
    <Bast_FarmDesc>This is a farm animal.</Bast_FarmDesc>
    <Bast_EggLayerDesc>This animal will periodically lay eggs.</Bast_EggLayerDesc>
    <Bast_WeirdEaterDesc>This animal eats a very strange variety of foods.<Bast_WeirdEaterDesc>
	<Bast_LivingFireExtinguisherDesc>When damaged via ranged attacks this animal will burst, emitting a supersonic puff of air extinguishing all flames nearby.</Bast_LivingFireExtinguisherDesc>
	<Bast_LivingEMPBlastDesc>When damaged via ranged attacks this animal will burst, emitting a large EMP blast.</Bast_LivingEMPBlastDesc>
    <Bast_LivingSmokeScreenDesc>When damaged via ranged attacks this animal will burst, engulfing the surrounding area in thick smoke.</Bast_LivingSmokeScreenDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedSharpDesc>This animal will use ranged attacks which inflict cutting damage.</Bast_DamageRangedSharpDesc>
	<Bast_DamageRangedAcidDesc>This animal will use highly corrosive ranged attacks to inflict lasting acidic damage.</Bast_DamageRangedAcidDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedFlameDesc>This animal will spew blazing flames towards its target, most likely lighting anything in between on fire.</Bast_DamageRangedFlameDesc>
    <Bast_DamageRangedPlasmaDesc>This animal will shell out devastating plasma-based ranged attacks which carry the heat of an entire sun.</Bast_DamageRangedPlasmaDesc>

</LanguageData>